<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>tech.agilitynerd - html</title><link href="https://tech.agilitynerd.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://127.0.0.1:8000/feeds/tag.html.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://tech.agilitynerd.com/</id><updated>2010-07-08T21:03:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Embedding JSON Within Generated HTML</title><link href="https://tech.agilitynerd.com/embedding-json-within-generated-html.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-08T21:03:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-07-08T21:03:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:tech.agilitynerd.com,2010-07-08:/embedding-json-within-generated-html.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ran into an interesting problem at work this past week that had a simple
and pleasing resolution. We have an in house developed JavaScript grid
on some of our pages and when users entered some text strings we'd
generate invalid &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.json.org/js.html"&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt; payloads that would give the user an error
page …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ran into an interesting problem at work this past week that had a simple
and pleasing resolution. We have an in house developed JavaScript grid
on some of our pages and when users entered some text strings we'd
generate invalid &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.json.org/js.html"&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt; payloads that would give the user an error
page. If they entered strings that looked like an HTML Entity i.e. &amp;amp;#13
which (with the addition of a trailing ; ) is a non-visible HTML
character (carriage return) the text wasn't displayed in the widget. To
further complicate things some of the content displayed in the grid is
HTML which is inserted into the grid as is and can contain escaped HTML
characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grid gets its content as a JSON payload from within a hidden div in
the HTML which is generated via a template mechanism. Heres a portion of
the template where &amp;lt;%= and %&amp;gt; stringifying of the value of the Python
variable(s)/code they surround:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;display:none;&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;grid-init-args-&amp;lt;%= count %&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;textarea&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;!-- this is the JSON payload loaded via the grid JavaScript --&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;%= [ columnsIndex, indexColumns, columns, rowBuffer, footerRows, formulas] %&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/textarea&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has a number of problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By using the template mechanism to create the JSON payload this
template was relying on the similarity of the string representation
of Python objects to JSON. After some testing I found the following
scenarios: If a string contained a single quote character the string
representation was a double quoted string around the text and the
single quote; a valid JSON string. If the string contained a double
quote character the string representation was a single quoted string
around the text and the double quote; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/388-People-Please-Stop-Using-Single-Quotes-.htm"&gt;an invalid JSON string&lt;/a&gt;. If
the string contained both a single and a double quote the string
representation would be a single quoted string containing a slash
escaped single quote and the double quote; an invalid JSON string.
Depending on the browser (of course) the JSON string would fail to
parse correctly when the double quote was encountered within the
single quoted string.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The JSON payload had to be HTML encoded (converting &amp;lt;, &amp;gt;, &amp;quot;, and &amp;amp;)
since it was parsed by the browser as HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The HTML encoding would encode or double encode HTML to be inserted
directly into the grid's DOM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variation in single/double quoting was an easy fix, I changed to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/simplejson/"&gt;simplejson&lt;/a&gt;.dumps() which correctly double quotes key/values in dicts
and escapes embedded double quotes (single quotes don't need to be
escaped). I didn't time it but with the C extension it may be faster
than the template engine for our larger datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played around with (not) encoding various portions of the payload and
then it hit me that I should change the grid to get its payload from a
non HTML element so that only HTML destined for insertion into the DOM
would be HTML encoded (which is as you'd expect for normal HTML
handling). I started changing the payload to be stored in JavaScript
generated in the template but didn't like the impact the change would
have on all the existing templates. So I started Googling and found &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/1603-jQuery-And-Script-Tags-As-Data-Containers.htm"&gt;Ben
Nadel's blog post on using script tags as data containers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's my solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;display:none;&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;grid-init-args-&amp;lt;%= count %&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;%= simplejson.dumps([ columnsIndex, indexColumns, columns, rowBuffer, footerRows, formulas]) %&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;simplejson.dumps&lt;/tt&gt; to correctly double quote and escape double
quotes within the variables in the payload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the textarea to a script element.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By converting to a script tag within the hidden div the HTML parser no
longer parsed the content of the JSON payload. so the JSON payload only
needed to HTML encode HTML elements that were being inserted into the
DOM created by the grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change also meant I was able to delete the unnecessary HTML
encoding of non-HTML JSON payload data. Got to love solutions that
involve deleting code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we'll convert to loading the JSON payload as a separate AJAX
request from the page to the server, but for now this simplifies the
markup and handles all types of user input and HTML encoded characters
correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="html"></category><category term="javascript"></category><category term="json"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="webdevelopment"></category></entry><entry><title>Multiple YouTube Videos per page using VideoLightBox</title><link href="https://tech.agilitynerd.com/multiple-youtube-videos-per-page-using-videol.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-04T22:58:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-06-04T22:58:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:tech.agilitynerd.com,2010-06-04:/multiple-youtube-videos-per-page-using-videol.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to stop displaying the default &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtube.com"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; video players within
posts on my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://agilitynerd.com/"&gt;AgilityNerd blog&lt;/a&gt; and I started looking for a light boxed
player. Their were two main reasons. The smallest video playback window
provided by YouTube for HD videos is too wide for my two column layout
and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to stop displaying the default &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtube.com"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; video players within
posts on my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://agilitynerd.com/"&gt;AgilityNerd blog&lt;/a&gt; and I started looking for a light boxed
player. Their were two main reasons. The smallest video playback window
provided by YouTube for HD videos is too wide for my two column layout
and now that I'm posting more videos the load time of the page is
delayed by the communication with all the off site webservers; serving
the YouTube static image of the video will be much faster/lighter
weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked around and really liked the lightbox containing the default
YouTube player provided by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://videolightbox.com"&gt;VideoLightBox&lt;/a&gt; and started playing around
with their demo. VideoLightBox (VLB) has an interesting approach. You
download an application (PC or Mac), configure how you want your
video(s) to look and it generates a directory of files on your local
disk (or uploads files to your website via FTP) along with an index.html
file from which you copy the code to put in the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; of
your web page. For YouTube it also downloads a static image for each
selected video which is used as the image link within the HTML page.
Straight forward and works well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my purposes there was a problem with their approach, its locates the
image used to launch the light box using an element id. This assumes a
single video or gallery of videos per web page. On my blog's main page
or the category pages there will be multiple videos (possibly multiple
videos within a single post). I figured a little bit of CSS and JQuery
hacking would solve the problem and it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to modify their HTML/CSS/JS to use a CSS class instead of an
element id to allow for multiple videos per page. At first I just
modified the generated files. Then I saw that VLB has template files in
their installation. So I started modifying the templates to output the
new code. Two hours later I bailed. Using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/bb896645.aspx"&gt;procmon&lt;/a&gt; it looks like the
client app reads the template files but then doesn't actually use the
files to generate the output files(?). I was only able to modify one of
the three template files that needed to change and have it effect the
generated files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to provide my edits to the VLB developers in case they are
interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the solution is to edit one of the template files and then edit two
of the generated files; not ideal but once you put the generated files
on your webserver you'll probably not touch them unless you are changing
CSS styles. The modifications aren't hard but you need to be careful and
typos will definitely break things. You should backup the VLB directory
before your start or be prepared to uninstall and reinstall from their
installation program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to the VideoLightBox directory (i.e. C:Program Files
(x86)VideoLightBox)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the permissions on the templates subdirectory to give your
user full access to overwrite the files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each directory in the templates subdirectory open the
videolightbox.js file in an programming editor (a keyboard macro
makes this trivial):&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globally replace $(&amp;quot;#videogallery a[rel]&amp;quot;) with
$(&amp;quot;.videogallery a[rel]&amp;quot;).each(function(idx){$(this)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the end of the line and add });&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then generate the output files using the VLB executable for one or more
videos, saving the results to your local file system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to the output directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the index.html file in an programming editor&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globally replace #videogallery with .videogallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globally replace id=&amp;quot;videogallery&amp;quot; with class=&amp;quot;videogallery&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the engine/css subdirectory open the videolightbox.css file in an
programming editor&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globally replace #videogallery with .videogallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you can copy the files just as specified by the VLB installation
instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other change I'll be making for my deployment is to rename the video
images. They are named 0.png, 1.png, etc. I'm going to put them all in a
directory on my resource webserver so I'll rename the files and their
references in the code copied from the index.html to use the YouTube
video id.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be changing my existing web posts over to this new scheme over
time...&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="css"></category><category term="html"></category><category term="javascript"></category><category term="jquery"></category><category term="video"></category><category term="visuallightbox"></category><category term="webdevelopment"></category><category term="youtube"></category></entry></feed>