<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>tech.agilitynerd - sysadmin</title><link href="http://tech.agilitynerd.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://127.0.0.1:8000/feeds/tag.sysadmin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tech.agilitynerd.com/</id><updated>2007-12-29T23:16:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Image Theft Ranting And Blocking</title><link href="http://tech.agilitynerd.com/image-theft-ranting-and-blocking-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-29T23:16:00-06:00</published><updated>2007-12-29T23:16:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:tech.agilitynerd.com,2007-12-29:/image-theft-ranting-and-blocking-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was really disappointed yesterday when I checked my blog's statistics
and found that someone from a Hungarian Agility discussion board had
directly linked course images from my website. Direct linking of an
image is placing the URL of the image directly in a webpage hosted on
another server. Each …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was really disappointed yesterday when I checked my blog's statistics
and found that someone from a Hungarian Agility discussion board had
directly linked course images from my website. Direct linking of an
image is placing the URL of the image directly in a webpage hosted on
another server. Each time a browser loads that page the direct link
causes the other server to send the image to the client's browser. So
each time the forum is viewed my server has to send the images to the
forum's viewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purposely try to make my image sizes small to make it possible for
dial up visitors to view my site without too much delay. So direct
linking doesn't impact my bandwidth costs too much; so far it is about
1Mb a day. The additional burden it puts on the webserver should be
small too, but since I don't own the shared server I don't really know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ranting"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ranting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aspect of this that most irritates me is that someone would copy my
work without attribution. That is the only thing I ask of visitors to my
site who wish to reuse my content. The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/"&gt;license link&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom of
each page should make this clear. I really don't think this is it too
much to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take copyright infringement very seriously. To me it isn't just the
legal requirements of using other's material in accordance with their
wishes that is important, taking credit, explicitly or implicitly, for
another's work is just wrong. This is one of those &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.robertfulghum.com/books.php#book1"&gt;All I Really Need To
Know I Learned In Kindergarten&lt;/a&gt; concepts: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.peace.ca/kindergarten.htm"&gt;Don't take things that
aren't yours&lt;/a&gt;. As a friend of Nancy's says &amp;quot;Some people don't have good
home training&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the Agility community is still a small community and the online
Agility community even more so. I guess I am naive, but I hoped that the
members of our community wouldn't do things like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="blocking"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Blocking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first step was emailing the webmaster of the site. The site was
entirely in Hungarian so it is possible the webmaster may not have
understood my English request. In any event, after 24 hours they hadn't
removed the links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went to look for a technical solution. There are a few well known
technical solutions for this problem. A search of Google for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/search?q=blocking+direct+linking"&gt;blocking
direct linking&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/search?q=blocking+hotlinking"&gt;blocking hotlinking&lt;/a&gt; will turn them all up. The
most useful solutions include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename the direct linked images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This mean updating all posts one your site to match the new name.
But if you only have a few images and/or posts to them you can do this on a per direct link basis.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Randomly generate image file names that change over time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is usually used for photo galleries where there is no text referring to each image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Serve images through a script&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script would reject requests for images based on information in
the request. This can be a compute intensive approach since it causes
requests even from your own site to go through the script. For sites
where you don't have control over the webserver this may be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Use a Rewrite rule to serve a different image to non-local referers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the technique I used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://altlab.com/htaccess_tutorial.html"&gt;altlab.com article&lt;/a&gt; I originally added these rules to my
.htaccess file on my server:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} !^$
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} !^http://(www.)?agilitynerd.com/.\* [NC]
RewriteRule .\*.(jpg\|jpeg\|gif\|png\|bmp)$ /images/nodirectlink.g [L,NC]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then created an image called nodirectlink.g shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="redirected-image"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Redirected Image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="p_embed p_image_embed"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" src="http://data.agilitynerd.com/images/nodirectlink.g" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't use the same filename suffix as one of the real image filenames
you use or you'll loop the rewrite engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had forgotten about images direct linked by RSS feed readers that
access the root. Rather than rewrite those requests I moved my Rewrite
rules into the .htaccess file in the images directory. I also decided to
not send the image after all, I'll just fail the request. There is no
sense in even wasting the bandwidth, the clients will now get the broken
image icon from their browser. The official &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://httpd.apache.org/docs/1.3/misc/rewriteguide.html"&gt;Apache URL Rewriting
Guide&lt;/a&gt; describes this in the Blocked Inline-Images section. So here is
my final solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} !^$
RewriteCond %{HTTP_REFERER} !^http://(www.)?agilitynerd.com/.\*$ [NC]
RewriteRule .\*.(jpg\|jpeg\|gif\|png\|bmp)$ - [F]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took this opportunity to modify some of my very first articles and
move their images into the /images directory. Those images were being
served by the Blosxom binary plugin back when I thought it was a
good idea. Now I won't pay any extra processing cost for those images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I have a technical solution to a human problem. There is a chance
that this change may cause some viewers of this site to not see images
on this site. But hopefully that should be a very, very small number of
people. But if you think you are getting my blocking image incorrectly
Please email me: steve at agilitynerd.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still disappointed I was forced to resort to this change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="apache"></category><category term="sysadmin"></category></entry><entry><title>Backup Your Data Lately?</title><link href="http://tech.agilitynerd.com/backup-your-data-lately-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-08-20T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2004-08-20T19:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:tech.agilitynerd.com,2004-08-20:/backup-your-data-lately-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I bought a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ximeta.com/products/network_drives/netdisk/index.php"&gt;Ximeta NetDisk&lt;/a&gt; 120 GB external hard drive
to back up the data on my home computers. There are a number of vendors
making hard drives that support USB connections; this model is unique in
that it also supports direct ethernet connections. Unlike more …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I bought a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ximeta.com/products/network_drives/netdisk/index.php"&gt;Ximeta NetDisk&lt;/a&gt; 120 GB external hard drive
to back up the data on my home computers. There are a number of vendors
making hard drives that support USB connections; this model is unique in
that it also supports direct ethernet connections. Unlike more expensive
Network Attached Storage devices (more than $ 1000) this unit only cost
a little more than the hard drive itself; about $ 150. The only downside
is that it uses it's own proprietary network protocol which requires
installation of a driver on any computers using the drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was to put this drive on my network switch and back up data from
my XP, WinME, RedHat 8.0, and Win95 machines. It turns out this was a
little trickier than I expected. So I spent the better part of the
morning on a cool, grey Chicago day making this all work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disk comes formatted for NTFS but in order for it to be shared on
the older Windows platforms and my Linux machine it needs to be
reformatted to use a FAT32 file system. Windows XP doesn't support
formatting drives for FAT32 so I had to install the Ximeta driver
software on my WinME machine and install the NetDisk on my network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running fdisk and reformatting the hard drive is the only &amp;quot;scary&amp;quot; aspect
of the installation. Choosing the wrong drive or partition would be a
&lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; thing. This &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ximeta.com/support/guides/netdisk/ndas/98seme/05.php"&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; gives a good step by step description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was skeptical that running fdisk over the network would work
correctly, but it did. At this point I was able to view the drive on
both my WinME and XP systems and copy data to the drive as if it was
locally connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty sure making the drive work for Linux would be difficult.
Unfortunately, the PDF documents from the Ximeta website are unreadable
as they require installing the Korean Acrobat extensions... thankfully
Google has its &amp;quot;View has HTML&amp;quot; facility which let me read the RedHat
instructions. The docs on the install CDROM are viewable (but don't
include the RedHat docs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll spare you all the trial and error but after downloading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ximeta.com/support/downloads/red_hat_8/index.php"&gt;driver
RPM&lt;/a&gt; from the website and installing it I couldn't configure and
connect to the drive on the network. It could be that ports required for
their protocol aren't opened on my Linux machine, but Ximeta doesn't
give any information on what ports are used by their driver. The admin
tool gives some cryptic error messages that Googling and the docs didn't
explain (the docs recommend reinstalling the drivers for any errors...).
I ended up connecting the drive directly via USB and was able to mount
the drive and backup my user and system accounts to the disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it looks like my goal of leaving the drive on the network and copying
to it from any computer will only work for Windows machines. But at
least I have a mechanism for backing up all my machines, that is easy
enough that I'll use it all the time. My next step is looking into
configuring &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rsync.samba.org"&gt;rsync&lt;/a&gt; or a similar mechanism to only backup the changed
files to the NetDisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, I'd recommend this drive for anyone who is using Windows XP;
it is plug and play for that operating system. If you are computer savvy
you can make this hard drive play with other systems too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However you do it, &lt;strong&gt;backup your computer!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="sysadmin"></category></entry></feed>