<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>tech.agilitynerd</title><link href="http://tech.agilitynerd.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://127.0.0.1:8000/feeds/tag.sitedesign.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tech.agilitynerd.com/</id><updated>2008-02-04T05:34:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Web Site Themes for Techies</title><link href="http://tech.agilitynerd.com/web-site-themes-for-techies-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-04T05:34:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:tech.agilitynerd.com,2008-02-04:web-site-themes-for-techies-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm no graphic artist so when it comes time to create or change the look
of my website I always have a difficult time. So I've discovered some
tools and tips that might help other non artists create reasonable
looking websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the general approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select an existing template or layout to use as a framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a photo or logo that represents the theme/color scheme of the
website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a background or background image using a sample of the
photo/logos color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample colors from the background, photo or logo for highlighting
other elements of the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll present how I applied this approach to my latest website makeover
and I'll discuss a some websites/tools I found helpful in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="selecting-a-layout"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Selecting a Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I don't have any suggestions for templates for specific
blog engines (apart from searching with Google). But I'll try to make up
for that with my next discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with using CSS for website customization Alessandro
Fulciniti has created a set of 40 one, two, and three column layouts on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.html.it/layoutgala/"&gt;his website&lt;/a&gt;. They are straight forward to follow if you've done any
CSS coding. If you haven't please skip ahead to the next section for
some other tips that might be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit to having some problem retrofitting my old CSS design.
My issue was with the rendering of the right hand column. When the
negative offset for the column was larger than the right margin for the
containing div the right column would be rendered at the bottom of the
page. It would look OK in Firefox but not in IE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course it is important to test any new layout in at least Internet
Explorer and Firefox. Now that Safari is available for Windows it is
easy to test on that browser as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="select-a-photo-or-logo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Select a Photo or Logo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have a color logo that you use for your business then you
can help reinforce that logo by using those colors in your site design.
Since my logo is currently black and white that didn't help me much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking to change my site to reflect the winter season so I went
to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sxc.hu/"&gt;StockXCHNG&lt;/a&gt; and found a nice royalty free &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sxc.hu/photo/911036"&gt;snow scene&lt;/a&gt; by
photographer &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sxc.hu/profile/ijsendoorn"&gt;ijsendoorn&lt;/a&gt;. There are thousands of interesting photos
suitable for use in blogs hosted on Stock.XCHNG, it is a great resource
and I heartily thank the photographers who post their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then used the free &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gimp.org/"&gt;Gimp&lt;/a&gt;image editing software to select a section
of the appropriate size for the header of my site. The Gimp is easy to
use and there is a fair amount of online help available if you are doing
something tricky. Of course you can use Photoshop or a similar program
if you have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="create-a-background"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Create a Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an area where I was really at a loss. I've never been good at
creating graphics, and a tileable image is even harder to create. There
are some tutorials you can find via Google but I just wasn't up for the
challenge. Of course you can use a complementary solid color background
by sampling your photo or logo (see the next section).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately I came across a software program called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ransen.com/Gliftex/Default.htm"&gt;Gliftex - An
Infinity of Tileable Graphics Designs&lt;/a&gt;. This is an interesting program
that can create a multitude of different images suitable for tiling
across the background of a web page. Gliftex has a number of algorithms
for choosing the form, color scheme, and interpretation and generating
images. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://graphicssoft.about.com/od/productreviews/l/aaglifticintro.htm"&gt;Here is a good overview&lt;/a&gt; of the product along with some
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gliftex has a feature that makes it perfect for creating a tileable
background image for a website, it can sample an image and use the
colors in the image as its palette of colors. So I took my snow scene
section and had Gliftex sample it. I pressed the Form and Interpretation
buttons a number of times and after a while came up with these
understated and simple tileable images:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" src="http://data.agilitynerd.com/images/bluebg05.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="image1" src="http://data.agilitynerd.com/images/bluebg03.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="image2" src="http://data.agilitynerd.com/images/bluebg02.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="image3" src="http://data.agilitynerd.com/images/bluebg01.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As far as I'm concerned the $ 50 US for the Gliftex Home download was a
great investment. They have a free demo version available for download
if you want to play around before you buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sample-colors-for-highlights"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sample Colors for Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I had an image for the header and a repeating image for the
background. I just needed to add some matching highlights for some other
areas of my blog to tie the whole theme together. I decided to color the
headings of my right and left sidebars to match one of the darker colors
of the header image. But how to pick out colors from the image?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gimp to the rescue again. I loaded my image again and selected Tools &amp;gt;
Color Picker. You are then presented with an eye dropper pointer. I just
clicked on interesting colors in my image to obtain a color value that I
could type into my theme's style sheet for the background colors. In the
picture below you can see the color value is &amp;quot;bec7d0&amp;quot; which you would
write as #bec7d0 in the style sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image4" src="http://data.agilitynerd.com/images/GimpColorPicker.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="results"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are an many additional changes to my theme I could make I am
pretty happy with the cool, blue-ish, wintry theme I've created:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image5" src="http://data.agilitynerd.com/images/blog_snow_theme_thumb.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://agilitynerd.com/blog/"&gt;AgilityNerd&lt;/a&gt;to see it in action or, depending on when
you read this, to see my next seasonal theme. I hope some of these tips
might be helpful for helping you create your next theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="sitedesign"></category></entry><entry><title>Stock.XCHNG - Free Stock Photos</title><link href="http://tech.agilitynerd.com/stockxchng-free-stock-photos-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-19T19:41:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:tech.agilitynerd.com,2008-01-19:stockxchng-free-stock-photos-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking at templates for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.zen-cart.com/"&gt;ZenCart&lt;/a&gt; and came across some templates
that use images from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sxc.hu/"&gt;Stock.XCHNG&lt;/a&gt;. Over an hour ago I started browsing
the images and am really impressed with the quality and breadth of
photos that artists are making available for free use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll definitely use some of these images to spice up my sites.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="sitedesign"></category></entry><entry><title>Online Button Creation Tool</title><link href="http://tech.agilitynerd.com/online-button-creation-tool-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-12-08T20:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:tech.agilitynerd.com,2004-12-08:online-button-creation-tool-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blosxom.sourceforge.net/"&gt;Blosxom&lt;/a&gt; email list tonight and came across an
interesting &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rbpark.ath.cx"&gt;photoblog by Rob Park&lt;/a&gt;. After enjoying some of his photos,
I noticed his &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rpbark.ath.cx/news/buttons.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kalsey.com/tools/buttonmaker"&gt;online form for creating the XML, RSS,
etc. buttons&lt;/a&gt; popular on so many websites. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kalsey.com"&gt;Adam Kalsey&lt;/a&gt; has created a
simple (dare I say elegant?) form that gives you just enough inputs to
completely control the look of the buttons. The image is generated in
PNG format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had I known of this site before it would have saved me a couple hours
messing around with Fireworks creating the buttons on my AgilityNerd
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://agilitynerd.com/blog/static/subscribe.html"&gt;Feeds&lt;/a&gt; page...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="sitedesign"></category><category term="tools"></category></entry></feed>